Alaa Abdulrahman SeedAhmed Alfaki

LEAD UI/UX DESIGNER

I'm a Human - Centered Designer with 4 years of experience in (Visual Design "UI & UX"). I thoroughly enjoy bringing products to life, starting with people's needs and ending with stunning interfaces that are as impactful as they are a joy to use.

Work Experience

Innovation Gate / UI/UX Designer

JUL 2022 - Present, KSA Remotly - Contract

- Gathering and evaluating user requirements, collaboration with **planning team**
- Design graphic user interface elements, like menus, tabs and widgets

GLT | Global Logistics & Technology / Team Lead UI/UX Designer

FEB 2022 - Present, Sudan-Khartoum - Contract

- Collaborate with project management and developers to define and implement innovative solutions for the product direction, visuals and experience.
- $\bullet\,$ Developed new design system for a large-scale payment app in sudan.
- Redesign a dashboard for electronic payment gateway.

Oasis Computer Systems / Visual Designer

JAN 2022 - FEB 2022, Sudan-Omdurman - Contract

• Designed website for **car insurance** with new methods and different innovation. Include navigation, layout, calls to action, and other interactive components.

Ibtikar soft for technical solutions / UX Designer

OCT 2020 - May 2021, Khartoum North - Contract

- Designing UI elements and tools such as **navigation menus**, **search boxes**, **tabs**, **and widgets** for our digital assets.
- $\bullet\,$ Designed ideas using various methods and latest technology using ADOBE XD & FIGMA.
- Worked on a diverse set of projects, working from research to production, that include iOS, Android and web (5 apps ,

One Fun App and 5 websites).

• Used agile development to identify problems and formulate solutions.

Design Projects

Sukoon / UI/UX Designer

SEP 2022 - OCT 2022, Khartoum

- Developed (Sukoon) mobile app, it's an application for books and novels.
- Built a completely different **user experience** from what the application was before based on certain requirements to suit **Sudanese minds** with different cultures and mentalities.
- Designed a stunning interfaces that are as impactful as they are a joy to use.

WeDo Technology / Visual Designer

JUL 2021 - DEC 2021, Khartoum North

- Redesign the mobile app (Sudan News Agency SUNA).
 Developed high-fidelity wireframes, clickable prototypes and conducted usability tests.
 Designed (Alfarabi) E-Learning app that helps many
- many student connect together easy.

Full Vision For Information Systems / UX Designer

JUN 2021 - JUL 2021, KSA Remotly

 Designed strategy on the insights of real users and data and turn these insights into beautifully designed experience across (Inaam Darren Fresh Meat) product.

Qatar Voluntary Centre / UI/UX Designer

MAR 2021 - MAY 2021, QAR Remotly

- Designed (Qatar Voluntary Centre "QVC") Met client , worked closely with project manager and collect inbound information and product criteria.
 Worked with developers to track, measure, and optimize user
- interfaces and experience.

Contact

- Khartoum North, Sudan
- +249990322624
- 🖂 alaa.a.alfaki@gmail.com
- https://www.behance.net/ alaaabdalrhman
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/alaaalfaki-9667a81b7/

Education

• B.sc (Sharq El Niel College – School of Computer Sciences & Information Technology – Department of Computer Sciences). 2015 – 2019

Google Career Certificate Program

- Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design .
- Start the UX Design process:
 Empathize, Define, and Ideate.
- Build Wireframes and Low-Fidelity Prototypes .
- Conduct UX Research and Test Early Concepts

Coursera Scholarship Certificate

- Design a User Interface (UI) Story Map in Miro .
- Work with Components in Figma .

Skills

- Workflows trough collaborative methodologies such as Design Thinking, Design Sprint or Lean UX
- Ability to analyze to identify improvement and problems of usability through heuristic evaluation guidelines
- Research, data analysis and definition of objectives applying quantitative techniques
- Identification and creation of information architectures, flows through sketching and

flow diagrams

- User testing
- Prototyping
- UI Designing